Guide to the Whitman College Alpha Chi Omega records 1927-1999
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Whitman College Alpha Chi Omega records
1927-1999
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Alpha Chi Omega. Beta Zeta Chapter
WCA063
3 linear feet 3 boxes
Whitman College hosted the Beta Zeta chapter of the national social sorority Alpha Chi Omega from 1928 to 1983. The Alpha Chi Omega collection contains memorabilia and records related to the sorority.
Collection is open for research.
Alpha Chi Omega (also known as Alpha Chi or A Chi O) is a women's fraternity founded on October 15, 1885 at DePauw University. The Beta Zeta Chapter of Alpha Chi Omega, a national sorority, was chartered from local sorority Theta Chi Theta in 1928. It was the fifth sorority to be chartered at Whitman College during a very active period in Greek Life. Alpha Chi Omega shut down in 1983 after many years of dwindling pledge numbers. Their former chapter room later hosted the Whitman chapter of Alpha Phi.
The collection consists of articles, publications, records, memorabilia, correspondence, membership lists, and photographs related to the Whitman Chapter of Alpha Chi Omega.
Greek letter societies; Whitman College--History
Colleges and Universities
- 50th reunion materials, 1978-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alumnae: Isabelle Shanahan, 1927-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alumnae letters, circa 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alumni relations, 1982-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Centennial celebration: VHS tape, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ceremonies, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Chapter photo, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Convention materials, 1950-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1965-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Creed, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Crest, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Dance and event programs, 1931-1965 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
- Dissolution documents, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The first 50 years, 1885-1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- History of the fraternity, 1985-1916 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Meeting minutes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Membership books, 1959-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Membership register, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- The Lyre of Alpha Chi Omega, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Object 1)
- Memorabilia, undated (Box 3, Object 1-7)
- Napkins, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- National convention, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Newsletters, 1984-1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Newspaper articles, 1964-1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Notecards, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Philanthropic materials, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Photographs, 1927-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
- Recipes, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Social events, 1941-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Songs, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- "Through the Years", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Scrapbook: Theta Chi Theta to Alpha Chi Omega, 1928 (Box 2, Object 1-2)
- Recruitment directory, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)